Jules Feiffer
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Papers of Jules Feiffer 1919-1995 (bulk 1950-1990)
MSS83993
Feiffer, Jules
15,000 items 59 containers plus 3 oversize 25 linear feet
Manuscript Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Cartoonist, playwright, author, and illustrator. Family correspondence, appointment calendars, awards and citations, financial records, newspaper clippings of articles about Feiffer, general correspondence, art publication file, and writings relating primarily to Feiffer's novels and stage and screenplays.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
Names:
Feiffer, Jules; Allen, Steve, 1921-2000--Correspondence; Arkin, Alan--Correspondence; Baraka, Imamu Amiri, 1934- --Correspondence; Burnshaw, Stanley, 1906- --Correspondence; Caniff, Milton Arthur, 1907- --Correspondence; Crichton, Robert--Correspondence; Doctorow, E. L., 1931- --Correspondence; Hefner, Hugh M. (Hugh Marston), 1926- --Correspondence; Hellman, Lillian, 1906- --Correspondence; Just, Ward S.--Correspondence; Kubrick, Stanley--Correspondence; Lantz, Robert--Correspondence; Mailer, Norman--Correspondence; May, Elaine, 1932- --Correspondence; McCarthy, Eugene J., 1916-2005--Correspondence; McGovern, George S. (George Stanley), 1922- --Correspondence; Nichols, Mike--Correspondence; Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1929-1994--Correspondence; Osborn, Robert Chesley, 1904- --Correspondence; Reiner, Carl, 1922- --Correspondence; Riley, Ted--Correspondence; Roth, Philip--Correspondence.; Schlesinger, Arthur Meier, 1917---Correspondence; Schulz, Charles M.--Correspondence; Sondheim, Stephen--Correspondence; Sorel, Edward, 1929---Correspondence; Trudeau, G. B., 1948---Correspondence; Wertham, Fredric, 1895-1981--Correspondence; Feiffer family; Feiffer family--Correspondence; Playboy Enterprises--Correspondence; Feiffer, Jules. Carnal knowledge (1971); Feiffer, Jules. God bless (1968); Feiffer, Jules. Knock, knock: a play (1976); Feiffer, Jules. Little murders (1968); Feiffer, Jules. Popeye, the movie novel (1980)
Subjects:
American drama; American fiction; Caricatures and cartoons; Motion picture plays; United States--Politics and government
Occupations:
Authors; Cartoonists; Illustrators; Playwrights
Administrative Information
Provenance:
The papers of Jules Feiffer, cartoonist, playwright and author, were donated to the Library of Congress by Feiffer in 1997.
Transfers:
Items have been transferred from the Manuscript Division to other custodial divisions of the Library. Drawings and photographs have been transferred to the Prints and Photographs Division. Motion picture films and audiotapes have been transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division. Some comic books have been transferred to the Serial and Government Publications Division. All transfers are identified in these divisions as part of the Jules Feiffer Papers.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1929, Jan. 26 Born, New York, N.Y.
1946 Attended Art Students League, New York, N.Y.
1946-1951 Assistant to cartoonist Will Eisner for comic book “The Spirit”
1947-1951 Attended Pratt Institute Art School, Brooklyn, N.Y.
1949-1951 Syndicated cartoon strip, “Clifford”
1951-1953 United States Army, Signal Corps; worked in cartoon animation unit
1953-1956 Held various positions in the art field, including producer of slide films, writer for CBS Films, Inc. “Terrytoons,” and designer of booklets
1956-1997 Published cartoon strip in the Village Voice originally entitled “Sick, Sick, Sick,” soon changed to “Feiffer”
1957 Published
Passionella and Other Stories (New York: McGraw Hill. 190 pp.)
1958 Published
Sick, Sick, Sick (New York: McGraw Hill. 130 pp.)
Illustrated
My Mind Went All to Pieces by Robert Mines (New York: Dial Press. 93 pp.)
1959 Began syndicating his cartoon strip, “Feiffer” Published
The Unexpurgated Memoirs of Bernard Mergendeiler (New York: Random House. 85 pp.)
1960 Published
The Explainers (New York: McGraw Hill. 120 pp.)
1961 Married Judith Sheftel (divorced 1983) Published
Boy, Girl, Boy, Girl (New York: Random House. 120 pp.)
Illustrated
The Phantom Tollbooth, by Norton Juster (New York: Epstein & Carroll. 256 pp.)
Recipient, George Polk Memorial Award
1963 Published
Harry, the Rat with Women (New York: McGraw Hill. 181 pp.),
Hold Me! (New York: Random House. unpaged.),
Feiffer's Album (New York: Random House. 132 pp.)
, and
Crawling Arnold (New York: Dramatists Play Service. 23 pp.)
1965 Published
Great Comic Book Heroes (New York: Dial Press. 189 pp.)
1966 Published
The Penguin Feiffer (Harmondworth, U.K.: Penguin. [121] pp.)
1967 Published
Feiffer's Marriage Manual (New York: Random House. 60 pp.)
1968 Published
Little Murders (New York: Random House. 113 pp.)
1970 Published
The White House Murder Case: A Play in Two Acts & Dick and Jane: A One-Act Play (New York: Grove Press. 122 pp.)
1971 Published
Carnal Knowledge: A Screenplay (New York: Farrar, Straus and Giroux. 117 pp.)
1973-1974 Taught at Yale Drama School, Yale University, New Haven, Conn.
1974 Published
Feiffer on Nixon: The Cartoon Presidency (New York: Random House. 64 pp.)
1976 Published
Knock, Knock: A Play (New York: Hill and Wang. 120 pp.)
1977 Published
Ackroyd: A Novel (New York: Simon and Schuster. 349 pp.)
and
Hold Me! An Entertainment (New York: Dramatists Play Service. 52 pp.)
1979 Published
Tantrum: A Novel in Cartoons (New York: Knopf. 183 pp.)
1982 Published
Jules Feiffer's America: From Eisenhower to Reagan, edited by Steven Heller (New York: Alfred A. Knopf. 254 pp.)
, and
Grown Ups: A Play (New York: Samuel French. 92 pp.)
1983 Married Jennifer Allen
1984 Published
Marriage Is an Invasion of Privacy, and Other Dangerous Views(Kansas City, Kan.: Andrews, McMeel & Parker. 128 pp.)
1986 Received Pulitzer Prize for editorial cartoons, a lifetime achievement award
1988 Published
Ronald Reagan in Movie America (Kansas City, Kan.: Andrews, McMeel & Parker. 128 pp.)
1990 Published
Elliot Loves: A Play (New York: Grove Press. 82 pp.)
1993 Published
The Man in the Ceiling (New York: HarperCollins. 185 pp.)
1995 Published
A Barrel of Laughs, A Vale of Tears (New York: HarperCollins. 180 pp.)
1997 Published
Meanwhile (New York: HarperCollins. 30 pp.)
1998 Published
I Lost My Bear (New York: Morrow Junior Books. ca. 40 pp.)
1999 Pulished
Bark, George (New York: HarperCollins. 30 pp.)
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Jules Ralph Feiffer (1929- ), cartoonist, playwright, and author, span the years 1919-1995 with the bulk dated from 1950 to 1990. The collection principally documents Feiffer's writing career and is organized in five series: Family and Biographical File, General Correspondence, Art Publications, Writings, and Oversize.
In 1956, Feiffer offered his cartoons to the Village Voice, just then making its reputation as a newspaper with influence beyond its locus in Greenwich Village in New York City. Feiffer's cartoons were simply-rendered drawings of people talking and explaining, talking to each other, to themselves, and, ostensibly, to the reader, sometimes in psychoanalytic language. His satire was compared to the stage acts of Elaine May and Mike Nichols, Mort Sahl, and Lenny Bruce. By the 1960s, when “Feiffer” was widely syndicated in the United States and Europe as a weekly strip, he turned his narrative sense and penchant for dialogue to writing novels and plays. Feiffer's cartooning style parallels his work for stage and screen in character development and theme, sometimes concentrating on relations between the sexes, as in his 1971 film Carnal Knowledge, other times exploring political and philosophical questions in Little Murders, God Bless, and Knock, Knock, and his youthful comic book heroes for the 1981 film, Popeye, all of which are well documented in the Writings series.
The Writings series comprises the largest group of papers. Included with drafts, notes, and background material is documentation on the publication or production of the work, such as correspondence and contracts, playbills and promotional material, and newspaper clippings of reviews and notices. The files for Carnal Knowledge also include legal documents concerning obscenity charges made against the film.
The Family and Biographical File features correspondence between Feiffer and his parents Rhoda and David Feiffer, and sisters, Alice and “Mimi,” during the 1950s when Feiffer was drafted into military service and in the early stages of his cartooning career. The series also includes appointment calendars, awards and citations, financial records for the years 1965-1980, high school records, legal documents, and newspaper clippings of articles about Feiffer.
The General Correspondence, organized in two parts as a chronological file and an alphabetical subject file, includes letters to Feiffer from friends, neighbors, acquaintances, fans and readers, writers, journalists, editors, publishers, cartoonists, academics, political activists, actors, directors, attorneys, and representatives of cultural, social, political, and religious organizations. The correspondence mostly concerns Feiffer's creative projects and includes comments sent by readers or audience members along with evaluations and reactions written by colleagues and friends in the publishing and theater worlds. Feiffer's political interests are also discussed in his correspondence and indicate his views and activities in behalf of various social issues in New York.
Frequent correspondents include Ted Riley, an agent who placed Feiffer's drawings in publication before they were widely syndicated, literary agent Robert Lantz, Hugh Hefner and Playboy Enterprises, and writers with whom Feiffer was friendly during sojourns to Martha's Vinyard, such as Robert Crichton and Ward Just. Other prominent correspondents include Steve Allen, Alan Arkin, Imamu Amiri Baraka, Stanley Burnshaw, Milton Arthur Caniff, E. L. Doctorow, Lillian Hellman, Stanley Kubrick, Norman Mailer, Elaine May, Eugene J. McCarthy, George S. McGovern, Mike Nichols, Jacqueline Kennedy Onassis, Robert Chesley Osborn, Carl Reiner, Philip Roth, Arthur Meier Schlesinger (1917- ), Charles M. Schulz, Stephen Sondheim, Edward Sorel, G. B. Trudeau, and Fredric Wertham.
The Art Publications series includes files relating to Feiffer's illustrations in advertisements, articles, and books, especially his own books of cartoon collections, as well as calendars, cards, cartoons, and comic strips. A small file documents exhibitions of Feiffer's drawings in museums and galleries.
Related Material
Drawings, photographs, and related material documenting Feiffer's career as a cartoonist are held by the Library's Prints and Photographs Division.
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in five series:
Family and Biographical File, 1919-1995, n.d.
General Correspondence, 1951-1993, n.d.
Art Publications, 1950-1995, n.d.
Writings, ca. 1940-1995, n.d.
Oversize, 1958-1989, n.d.
Container List
- Family and Biographical File, 1919-1995, n.d. (Box 1-8)
  Appointment calendars; awards, certificates, and citations; biographical sketches; family correspondence and papers relating to family members; financial records; interview transcripts; high school records; legal documents; and newspaper clippings of articles about Feiffer.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person, topic, or type of material and chronologically thereunder.
  - Appointment calendars See also Oversize (Box 1)
    - 1967-1983, (5 folders)
    - 1984-1992, (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Awards, certificates, and citations, 1958-1976, 1986-1989, 1995, n.d.
  - Biographical sketches, 1960-ca. 1980
  - Family correspondence with Feiffer
    - Feiffer, David and Rhoda (father and mother), 1919, 1950-1974, (5 folders)
    - Feiffer, Jennifer Allen (wife), 1981-1983 (Box 3)
    - Feiffer, Judy Sheftel (wife), 1941, 1961-1971
    - Feiffer, Kate (daughter), 1964-1990
    - Moody, Miriam (Mimi) Feiffer (sister), 1951-1988
    - Korman, Alice Feiffer (sister), 1945-1974
    - Other family members, 1964, n.d. See also Oversize
  - Feiffer, Jennifer Allen, papers
    - Correspondence, 1980-1986
    - Miscellany, 1972, 1978-1981
    - Writings
      - Articles and drafts, 1981-1983, n.d.
      - Notes and research material, n.d., (3 folders)
  - Financial records (Box 4)
    - Bernard Mergendeiler Corp., deposits, 1975-1980, (2 folders)
    - Royalty statements, plays and books, 1968-1979
    - Tax files
      - 1965-1970, (6 folders)
      - 1971-1980, (10 folders) (Box 5)
      - 1981-1992, (3 folders) (Box 6)
  - Interview transcripts, 1963, n.d.
  - James Monroe High School, Bronx, New York, N.Y., 1943-1946, 1963, 1976
  - Levinson v. United States, amici curiae briefs, 1969
  - Miscellany, 1959-1965, 1975-1980, 1990-1993, n.d.
  - Newspaper clippings and related material about Feiffer (Box 7)
    - 1957-1968, (9 folders)
    - 1969-1995, (5 folders) (Box 8)
- General Correspondence, 1951-1993, n.d. (Box 8-18)
  Letters received with occasional copies of Feiffer's response.
  Arranged as received in two parts as a chronological file and an alphabetical subject file.
  - Chronological file (Box 8)
    - 1951-1958 Correspondents include Steve Allen and Stanley Kubrick
    - 1959 Correspondents include Steve Allen, Stanley Kubrick, Charles M. Schulz, and Norman Thomas
    - 1960 Correspondents include Jacqueline Kennedy Onassis
    - 1961
      - Jan.-June Correspondents include Milton Caniff
      - July-Dec. Correspondents include Imamu Amiri Baraka, Arthur Meier Schlesinger (1917- ), and Eric Sevareid (Box 9)
    - 1962
      - Jan.-July, (2 folders)
      - Aug.-Dec. Correspondents include Milton Caniff, E. L. Doctorow, Edward Sorel, Rex Stout, and Louis Untermeyer
    - 1963
      - Jan.-June Correspondents include Art Buchwald, Herbert Gold, Rose Fitzgerald Kennedy, Norman Mailer, Norman Rosten, Dore Schary, and Arthur Meier Schlesinger (1917- )
      - July-Dec. Correspondents include Steve Allen, Walter Cronkite, Carl Reiner, and Abigail Van Buren
    - 1964
      - Jan.-Apr. Correspondents include William F. Buckley
      - May-Aug. Correspondents include E. L. Doctorow (Box 10)
      - Sept.-Dec. Correspondents include William F. Buckley and George Plimpton
    - 1965
      - Jan.-Mar.
      - Apr.-June Correspondents include Art Buchwald, E. L. Doctorow, and Norman Mailer
      - July-Sept. Correspondents include Milton Caniff, Clare Boothe Luce, and Benjamin Spock
      - Oct.-Nov. Correspondents include Will Eisner and Fredric Wertham
      - Dec. Correspondents include Fredric Wertham
    - 1966 (Box 11)
      - Jan.-May Correspondents include Al Capp, Paul Johnson, and Gene Kelly
      - June-Dec. Correspondents include Walter Cronkite, E. L. Doctorow, Rowland Evans, Mike Nichols, Robert Chesley Osborn, Jerome Robbins, and Bayard Rustin
    - 1967
      - Jan.-July Correspondents include William F. Buckley, Lillian Hellman, Elaine May, Mike Nichols, and Maurice Sendak
      - Aug.-Dec. Correspondents include William F. Buckley, William O. Douglas, Burton Lane, Dwight MacDonald, Norman Mailer, Mike Nichols, Arthur Meier Schlesinger (1917- ), and William Styron
    - 1968 Correspondents include Milton Caniff, Penelope Gilliatt, Tom Hayden, Ethel Kennedy, Coretta Scott King, Anthony Lewis, Eugene J. McCarthy, Philip Roth, and Arthur Meier Schlesinger (1917- )
    - 1969
      - Jan.-June Correspondents include Alan Arkin, Milton Caniff, Nathan Glazer, Lillian Hellman, Herbert Klein, Bernard Malamud, James Reston, and Arthur M. Schlesinger (1917- )
      - July-Dec. Correspondents include Alan Arkin, Milton Caniff, Anthony Perkins, Philip Roth, and Edward Sorel
    - 1970 (Box 12)
      - Jan.-June Correspondents include Will Eisner, Merv Griffin, Lillian Hellman, Ann Landers, Mike Nichols, and Philip Roth
      - July-Dec. Correspondents include Stanley Burnshaw, Elliott Gould, Buck Henry, Norman Rosten, and Studs Terkel
    - 1971
      - Jan.-June Correspondents include George Gallup, Lillian Hellman, Bernard Malamud, Jack Nicholson, George Plimpton, and Stephen Sondheim
      - July-Dec. Correspondents include Roddy McDowall and Philip Roth
    - 1972 Correspondents include William O. Douglas, George S. McGovern, and Adam Walinsky
    - 1973
      - Jan.-June Correspondents include Stephen Sondheim
      - July-Dec.
    - 1974
      - Jan.-June Correspondents include Jane Fonda, Shirley MacLaine, and Bernard Malamud
      - July-Dec.
    - 1975 (Box 13)
      - Jan.-June
      - July-Dec. Correspondents include Stanley Burnshaw, Dorothy Day, Groucho Marx, and Robert Chesley Osborn
    - 1976
      - Jan.-Apr. Correspondents include John Brooks and Barry Goldwater
      - May-Dec. Correspondents include Lillian Hellman
    - 1977
      - Jan.-June Correspondents include Russell Baker, Stanley Burnshaw, John Conyers, and Lillian Hellman
      - July-Dec., n.d. Correspondents include Nora Ephron
    - 1978 (Box 14)
      - Jan.-July Correspondents include David Halberstam
      - Aug.-Dec. Correspondents include Milton Caniff, John Hersey, and Carey McWilliams
    - 1979
      - Jan.-Aug. Correspondents include Milton Caniff and Mike Nichols See also Oversize
      - Sept.-Dec. Correspondents include Frances Fitzgerald, John Hersey, and Anthony Lewis
    - 1980, (2 folders)
    - 1981 (Box 15)
      - Jan.-July Correspondents include Alexander Cockburn, Jim Davis, and Mort Walker
      - Aug.-Dec. Correspondents include John Marquand and G. B. Trudeau
    - 1982
      - Jan.-Aug. Correspondents include Milton Caniff and David Halberstam
      - Sept.-Dec. Correspondents include Stanley Burnshaw, Lillian Hellman, Edward Sorel, and G. B. Trudeau
    - 1983 Correspondents include Stanley Burnshaw and Milton Caniff
    - 1984-1988 Correspondents include Will Eisner and Thomas B. Morgan
    - 1989
      - Jan.-July Correspondents include Stanley Burnshaw, Hume Cronyn, and Elliott Gould See also Oversize
      - Aug.-Oct. Correspondents include Garson Kanin and Anthony Lewis
      - Nov.-Dec., n.d. Correspondents include Norman Lear, Thomas B. Morgan, and Edward Sorel (Box 16)
    - 1990
      - Jan.-Aug. Correspondents include Roddy McDowall, Larry McMurtry, Bill Melendez, and Robert Chesley Osborn
      - Sept.-Dec. Correspondents include Adolph Green, Bill Melendez, Mike Peters, and Edward Sorel
    - 1991-1993 Correspondents include Edward Sorel
  - Subject file
    - Contracts, miscellaneous
      - 1957-1963
      - 1964-1991, (2 folders) (Box 17)
    - Crile, Susan, 1971-1980, n.d. See also Oversize
    - Permissions, play productions, 1966-1969
    - Playboy Club and Hugh Hefner, 1958-1990, (3 folders)
    - Robert Lantz Agency
      - 1961-1969
      - 1970-1991, (6 folders) (Box 18)
    - Yaddo (Artist colony), 1966-1991, (2 folders)
- Art Publications, 1950-1995, n.d. (Box 19-22)
  Illustrations created by Feiffer for advertisements, articles, books, calendars, cards, cartoons and comic strips, and records of exhibitions of his drawings.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of illustration and chronologically thereunder.
  - Advertisements, 1956-1964, n.d. See also Oversize (Box 19)
  - Articles, 1956-1976, 1992
  - Books
    - Boy, Girl, Boy, Girl, 1961-1963
    - Explainers, 1960-1961 See also Oversize
    - Feiffer's Album, 1963
    - Feiffer's America, 1983, n.d., (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 20)
    - Feiffer's Children, 1986, n.d.
    - Hold Me! 1963-1964
    - “Man in the Radical Middle,” 1960-1981, n.d., (2 folders)
    - Munro, 1961
    - My Mind Went All to Pieces by Robert Mines, 1959, n.d.
    - Passionella, 1959-1960, n.d. See also Oversize
    - The Phantom Tollbooth by Norton Juster, 1961-1962
    - Sick, Sick, Sick, 1958-1959 See also Oversize
    - Tantrum, 1979 (Box 21)
  - Calendars, 1966, 1977, 1983 See also Oversize. For additional material see Container 1, Appointment calendars, 1967
  - Cards, announcements, invitations, and miscellany, 1958-1988, n.d. See also Oversize, (2 folders)
  - Cartoons and comic strips
    - Drawings
      - 1950- 1959, (5 folders)
      - 1960-1980, 1986, 1995, n.d., (6 folders) (Box 22)
    - Notes, promotional material, and self portrait, 1969, n.d. See also Oversize
  - Exhibitions, 1958-1993, n.d.
- Writings, ca. 1940-1995, n.d. (Box 22-59)
  Drafts of articles, essays, nonfiction books, journal notes, novels, plays, speeches, and short stories along with records related to the publication or theatrical production of these works, including correspondence and contracts; film and theater production records such as photographs, playbills, promotional materials, and shooting schedules; financial records; legal documents; and newspaper clippings of reviews and reports on projects.
  - Articles, essays, and notes (Box 22)
    - 1957-1988, 1995, (3 folders)
    - Undated (Box 23)
      - Fragments
      - Miscellaneous articles
      - “Strip Time: The Comics Observed,” by Milton Caniff and Jules Feiffer, n.d.
  - Books, nonfiction
    - “Bouncy Bouncy Ballie: The Folk Rhymes and Street Chants of Children in the U.S.A.,” ca. 1955
    - Great Comic Book Heroes
      - Introduction, ca. 1965
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1965-1966
  - Journal notes, 1957, n.d.
  - Novels
    - Ackroyd
      - Correspondence and contract, 1976-1977
      - Drafts
        - First draft, n.d, (2 folders) (Box 24)
        - Revisions, n.d., (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 25)
        - Subsequent drafts, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box 26)
        - Final draft, 1976, (3 folders)
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1977-1978
    - A Barrel of Laughs, a Vale of Tears (juvenile)
      - Drafts
        - First draft, n.d.
        - Revisions, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 27)
        - Subsequent drafts, 1993-1995, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box 28)
      - Notes, n.d.
    - “The Big Glitter,” novel or screenplay ideas
      - Correspondence with Edward Sorel, n.d.
      - Notes, n.d.
    - “Car Ride” See also Containers 45-48, Little Murders
      - Drafts, 1964
      - Notes
        - “Little Murders,” n.d.
        - “The Mother Questions,” n.d.
    - Harry, the Rat with Women
      - Correspondence, contracts, and critique, 1961-1970, n.d.
      - Drafts
        - Fragments, n.d., (2 folders)
        - Full text, 1962, n.d., (4 folders) (Box 29)
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1963
      - Playscript, n.d.
    - “Little Murders” See Container 46 (Box 30)
    - The Man in the Ceiling
      - Drafts
        - Full text, 1992, (3 folders)
        - Revisions
          - Holograph, n.d.
          - Typescript, n.d., (2 folders)
          - Typescript and galley, n.d. (Box 31)
      - Newspaper clippings and related material, 1993
  - Plays
    - “Answers,” drafts of screenplay
      - Fragments, n.d.
      - Full text, 1971, (2 folders)
    - Anthony Rose
      - Playscript
        - Drafts
          - Fragments, n.d.
          - Full text, n.d., (3 folders)
        - Reading script, Philadelphia Festival for New Plays, Philadelphia, Pa., 1989 (Box 32)
      - Theater production and promotion records, 1988-1990
    - “Baby Pictures,” drafts of screenplay
      - Holograph, n.d.
      - Typescript, 1991
      - Revisions, n.d., (2 folders)
    - “Bea Plus”
      - Script for television, drafts, 1975, n.d.
      - Sketch for “Carol Burnett Special,” n.d.
    - “Bernard and Huey”
      - Contract, 1986
      - Drafts of screenplay
        - Fragments and notes
          - Holograph, n.d.
          - Typescript, 1987, n.d. (Box 33)
        - Full text, n.d
    - “Boomtown,” n.d.
    - Carnal Knowledge
      - Correspondence, 1969-1987
      - Dust jacket, n.d.
      - Film production
        - Financial statements, 1973-1978